<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.2xndj8"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0413674-210914110416597</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.2xndj8</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2022-08-02
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;and&quot; : [
    &quot;TaxonKey is one of (Tracheophyta, Lepidoptera)&quot;,
    &quot;BasisOfRecord is one of (Observation, Human Observation, Specimen)&quot;,
    &quot;StateProvince is one of (Maryland)&quot;,
    &quot;HasCoordinate is true&quot;,
    &quot;Year 1989-2021&quot;
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
1 records from SD - SD Herbarium, San Diego Natural History Museum
1 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
1 records from Brigham Young University Arthropod Museum
1 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
1 records from Royal Ontario Museum Green Plant Herbarium (TRT)
1 records from Eastern Kentucky University, Ronald L. Jones Herbarium
1 records from UCR - University of California, Riverside Herbarium - Vascular Plants
1 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
1 records from Desert Botanical Garden Herbarium
1 records from US herbarium - Smithsonian Institute - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from Cleveland Museum of Natural History
1 records from Appalachian State University, I. W. Carpenter, Jr. Herbarium
2 records from Mississippi Entomological Museum
2 records from Higher Plant Collections of the Lagos University Herbarium (LUH): Families A - Z
2 records from Aspilanta new genus (Heliozelidae) specimen data
2 records from Deaver Herbarium (Northern Arizona University)
2 records from Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University Insect Collection
2 records from Clemson University Herbarium
2 records from Western Washington University Insect Collection
3 records from Fairchild Tropical Botanic Garden (FTG)
3 records from University of Alabama Herbarium
3 records from Auburn University, John D. Freeman Herbarium
3 records from Rutgers University, Chrysler Herbarium
3 records from University of Georgia Collection of Arthropods
3 records from Essig Museum of Entomology
3 records from The Albert J. Cook Arthropod Research Collection
4 records from Clemson University Arthropod Collection
4 records from Bruce Bennett Herbarium (BABY)
4 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
5 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
6 records from University of Vermont, Pringle Herbarium
7 records from Marie-Victorin Herbarium (MT) - Plantes vasculaires
7 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
7 records from Biodiversity4all Research-Grade Observations
7 records from CONN
9 records from Digitalización y Sistematización de las Colecciones Biológicas Nacionales del Instituto de Biología, UNAM (Plantas vasculares)
9 records from Arizona State University Hasbrouck Insect Collection
10 records from Entomology Collection at the Natural History Museum of Utah
10 records from Plant Resources Center
10 records from Campbell University Herbarium
12 records from University of Minnesota Insect Collection
12 records from George Mason University, Ted R. Bradley Herbarium
12 records from USGS PWRC - Native Bee Inventory and Monitoring Lab (BIML)
13 records from Lepidoptera World (Luomus) (LEPW)
14 records from Frost Entomological Museum
15 records from USGS NRP - Submerged Aquatic Plants - 1966-2009
19 records from University of Florida Herbarium (FLAS)
19 records from NEON Biorepository Terrestrial Plant Collection (Herbarium Vouchers)
24 records from CHSC - CSU Chico, Chico State Herbarium - Vascular Plants
24 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
25 records from Invasive Plant Atlas of the MidSouth (IPAMS)
31 records from NEON Biorepository Terrestrial Plant Collection (Canopy Foliage)
35 records from C.A. Triplehorn Insect Collection (OSUC), Ohio State University
49 records from R. L. McGregor Herbarium Vascular Plants Collection
49 records from Academy of Natural Sciences Entomology Collection - LepNet
50 records from Towson University - MidAtlantic - Ailanthus altissima - 2011
59 records from Institut Botanic de Barcelona (IBB, CSIC-Ajuntament de Barcelona), BC-Plantae
70 records from University of Delaware Insect Research Collection
70 records from C.P. Gillette Museum of Arthropod Diversity
80 records from University of South Carolina, A. C. Moore Herbarium
99 records from San Diego Natural History Museum Entomology Department
103 records from MVSC; The James C. Parks Herbarium at Millersville University
110 records from Mississippi Museum of Natural Science Herbarium
120 records from University of Alberta E. H. Strickland Entomological Museum (UASM)
137 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
176 records from Entomology Division, Yale Peabody Museum
180 records from Academy of Natural Sciences of Drexel University
289 records from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium: Vascular Plants
416 records from University of South Florida Herbarium (USF)
426 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
514 records from The Lepidopterists&apos; Society Season Summary
644 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
3129 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records (USNM, US)
5824 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
9581 records from eButterfly Surveys
254593 records from iNaturalist Research-grade Observations</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2022-08-02T21:55:26Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.2xndj8">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.2xndj8</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0413674-210914110416597.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
